MOHAMED ARSHATH AMEEN

Full Stack Developer

Contact

E-mail

arshathameen505@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/mohamed-arshath-ameen-085336173

WWW

https://github.com/Ameen-Works

www

https://bold.pro/my/arshath-ameen/420

Skills

HTML, CSS & JS

Upper intermediate

JAVA

Intermediate

HCM Modules

Intermediate

Multitasking abilities

Upper intermediate

Project Management

Upper intermediate

Enthusiastic Full Stack Developer eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills. Clear understanding of Programming and Debugging and training in Software Proficiency. Motivated to learn, grow and excel in IT Industries for 2 years.

Work History

2021-11 -Current

Assistant System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services, Chennai

- Resolved conflicting design and system requirements during new equipment installation.
- Worked on API, XML-XSLT, Integration system design.
 Estimated work hours and tracked progress using Scrum methodology.
- Build, Test and Deploy minor integration and functional level configuration/ enhancements.
- Collaborated with customers to define systems engineering technical specifications and design parameters.

2021-06 -2021-10

Java Developer Intern

Haaris InfoTech, Chennai

- Learnt basics of JAVA, HTML and SQL
- Debugged and corrected computer programming errors with advisory from master developer.

2020-03 -2020-06

Shiash Info Solutions Private Limited, Chennai

Worked with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.

Education

2017-08 - 2021-07	Bachelor of Engineering - BE: Mechanical Engineering
	Dhaanish Ahmed College of Engineering - Chennai

CGPA: 8.9

Intern

2016-05 - HSC: Computer Science

17-06 THANTHAI PERIYAR GOVT.HR.SCHOOL - Karaikal

CGPA: 94

2014-05 - **SSLC**

2015-05 ST.MARY'S HR.SEC.SCHOOL - Karaikal

CGPA: 95

Certifications

2020-07	Java- Udemy
2020-07	C++ programming- Coursera
2020-08	Android studio- Coursera
2020-11	Social Media Marketing Foundations- LinkedIn